JOÃO PEDRO SCONETTO

Email: sconetto.joao@gmail.com Phone: +49 152 3789 6034

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sconetto **Twitter:** @sconetto **Skype:** sconetto **Website:** sconetto.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer, who graduated from Universidade de Brasília (UnB). I really enjoy working (and have experience) with all areas surrounding software development, like backend, frontend, software architecture, DevOps, databases, software documentation, and project management.

I'm drive to reach goals & results, a fast learner (and always want to learn new technologies), I like making people happy, collaborating with teams, sharing my knowledge, and making an impact on the world!

EXPERIENCE

СТО

much. GmbH / Munich, DE / May 2021 - Now

I'm working as an acting CTO @ much. in various areas, developing and applying standards, guaranteeing that customers' projects are on track, and making sure they're happy. I'm also responsible for all of our technical team and the owner of our cloud solution for ERP systems.

SENIOR TECHNICAL LEADER

much. GmbH / Munich, DE / June 2020 - May 2021

I was responsible for major customer projects, developing and applying standards, steering the technical team, and the company's knowledge management.

SENIOR ENGINEER

much. GmbH / Munich, DE / January 2020 - June 2020

I was responsible for the development and deployment of Python (ERP) & JavaScript (custom products) projects across the company.

RESEARCHER/ARCHITECT/BACKEND ENGINEER

Universidade de Brasília (UnB) / Brasília, BR / October 2018 - November 2019

I was a researcher, architect, and software engineer, building secure software with microservices and Function as a Service (FaaS) architecture. All solutions were focused on innovation, security, and reusability. Results from the

the development was used as a resource to write scientific articles.

WEB FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Brazilian Federal Senate / Brasília, BR / September 2017 - October 2018

I was responsible to develop and maintain web systems, scripts, and code tests in Python/Django/Angular and shell

(bash). I was also first-level support for issues in the senate House systems.

SUPPORT/SYSADMIN/DEVOPS MANAGER

Basis Tecnologia S.A. / Brasília, BR / June 2016 - September 2017

I was responsible to develop, maintain, and evolve Java/Groovy systems (JIRA), project and configuration

management, DevOps management (deployment & configuration), AD (LDAP) management, database systems maintenance, and user support.

PROJECTS

TUTOR/VOLUNTARY TEACHER

In 2017/2019 I was a tutor/volunteer teacher at the Universidade de Brasília (UnB) on the subject of Computer Architecture Fundamentals, where I helped other students with the subject fundamentals and Assembly programming. In 2015/2016 I was a tutor/volunteer teacher of Algorithms and Computer Programming with the same role.

PROJECT SRC

Owner, manager, and developer for the project named Project SRC, a microservice solution with a mobile app to manage racing leagues.

Link: github.com/Project-SRC

RADOP

In 2019 I was the technical manager and engineer of the RaDop project, a doppler effect radar for accident prevention on Brazilian roads.

Link: github.com/radar-pi

PARTIU!

In 2016 I participated in the Partiu! project as a full-stack engineer. The project was an app to share rides with friends. It was a hybrid application in Ionic with Ruby using the user's Facebook profile to verify their friend network.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Universidade de Brasília (UnB) / Brasília, BR / 2020 / 1.72 GPA

SKILLS

PYTHON / JAVASCRIPT / RESTRUCTURED TEXT / HTML5/CSS3 / GO / LINUX / IONIC / DOCKER / C/C++ / WINDOWS / AGILE / REACT / ASSEMBLY / SCRUM / SHELL SCRIPT / GIT / RUST / JAVA / EXTREME PROGRAMMING / LEAN / SAFE / REACT-NATIVE / SQL / RUBY / DESIGN PATTERNS / LATEX / MARKDOWN / VUE.JS / KUBERNETES / NOSQL / UML / MESSAGE QUEUE / MACOS / NODEJS / PORTUGUESE - NATIVE / ENGLISH - C2 / SPANISH - A2 / GERMAN - A2